Daniel Skowroński

@ daniel@skowron.ski

4 +48 507-188-312

◊ Krakow, Poland

% blog.dsinf.net in linkedin.com/in/daniel-skowronski github.com/danielskowronski

ABOUT ME

My main fields of interest (both professionally and as a hobby) are systems architecture, administration, computer networks and cybersecurity. I refer to myself as hacker (in original meaning of that word but also as whitehat researcher).

I have experience in many stages of computer system lifecycle - not only in typical business roles but also as fullstack freelancer as well as all-in-one IT guy on festivals and in students' association. That gives me advantage of being able to understand customer and business needs and manage resources (including time) with care. Another aspect of my career story - work in operations jobs allowed me to learn how to work under time pressure in disaster scenarios.

I'm advocate of Bill Gate's words "I choose a lazy person to do a hard job, because a lazy person will find an easy way to do it" - and really prefer to automate everything. I'm also constant learner - not only mastering current skills but also discovering new approaches and technologies.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior DevOps Engineer

Prescient Co

M October 2019 - Ongoing

◊ Krakow, Poland

My job is to be a bridge between Developement (with QA) and Operations (IT department) worlds - understanding how applications are supposed to behave and solutioning their high availability as well as keeping them updated. Important parts of this chapter in my career are implementing Infrastructure-as-a-Code paradigm, introducing new operating system (Linux) and containerization systems (Kubernetes) into existing ecosystem.

Linux Platform Engineer

Motorola Solutions Systems

May 2019 - October 2019

Y Krakow, Poland

As software developer in Dimetra Platform team I was responsible for the development of management and deployment tools for Linux platforms, as well as virtualization using VMware and KVM solutions.

I was also responsible for lab environment.

Platform Operations Engineer

Akamai Technologies

◊ Krakow, Poland

My responsibilities in Network Operations Command Center included responding to real time issues with entire Akamai platform - from routine hardware problems to global routing or capacity incidents which require immediate action. I participated in maintaining general network health, resolving configuration defects, performing network maintenance works and responding to outside communication with other NOCs and service providers.

Since 2018 I worked on senior level assignments which included approving potentially dangerous nonstandard operations, being part of incident coordination and deploying configuration changes. I also developed several software solutions that helped multiple departments in every day work.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Linux

Windows Server

Ansible Pvthon

Networks



STRENGTHS

Development

Python bash **PowerShell** SQL Go C# x86 assembly JavaScript

Virtualization and containerization

Proxmox VMware vSphere

KVM (libvirt) Docker Kubernetes (Rancher)

• DevOps/automation tools

Ansible **Jenkins Azure Pipelines**

Elasticsearch Grafana

Databases

MSSQL PostgreSQL MySQL

EDUCATION

Computer Science

Jagiellonian University in Cracow

2014 - 2016

LANGUAGES

Polish English



OTHERS

- Layer2 and Layer3 network maintenance and management (Cisco, Juniper, HP)
- TCP/IP and higher level protocols debugging (Wireshark)
- · security & whitehat hacking
- electronics

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

System Administrator

Computer Science Students' Association - KSI UJ

December 2014 – January 2018

◊ Krakow, Poland

My role as SysAdmin was to keep our network working and secure, maintain servers belonging to KSI including critical infrastructure (mail, DNS), develop applications that were used by management board, and supervise server room.

Another task of Administrator in KSI was to cooperate with network administrators of university.

Secretary of the Board

Computer Science Students' Association - KSI UJ

♥ Krakow, Poland

For 2 academic years I was also Secretary of the Board in KSI. As active member of board I also participated in organizing various events on UJ like *Malopolska Noc Naukowców* (Night of Scientists) and *Festiwal Nauki* (Science Festival).

Chief Information Officer

Academic IT Festival - SFI

math display="block" December 2014 - July 2017" December 2014 - July 2017

Y Krakow, Poland

I was member of logistics team, Chief Information Officer and web developer involved in development of contest application (PHP, later Erlang) and DevOps (Git, CI).

I also acted as SysAdmin being responsible for network infrastructure during event and helpdesk engineer dealing with end users.

IT Coordinator

Theatre Festival "Zwierciadla"

September 2012 - May 2014

Lublin, Poland

"Zwierciadla" is high school theatre festival organized by students. Since 2013 I was responsible for it's website and other IT and logistics related tasks like network configuration, helpdesk, coordinating multimedia processing and publishing etc.

That experience gave me early opportunity to learn team work and responsibility in the face of deadlines.

INTERESTS

- cybersecurity (whitehat-hacking)
- embedded systems
- electronics
- cloud computing
- · amateur photography
- Japanese culture

GDPR

I hereby give consent for my personal data included in my application to be processed for the purposes of the recruitment process under the European Parliament's and Council of the European Union Regulation on the Protection of Natural Persons as of 27 April 2016, with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC (Data Protection Directive)